

### Mohammad ali Ali panah

Software Engineer

mohammadali.ap.2000@gmail.com

+989197532677 🔇

Tehran, Iran 🔘





# **Story Book**

As a child, I grow up with endless love of computers. Started learning HTML, CSS, and JQuery at the age of I3 in MFT. Couldn't catch up back then because of poor knowledge of fundamentals, So I continued my journey several years later by learning C++ and Javascript in depth. this time was different and I feel the improvement every day. Nowadays, I spend most of my time at work structuring and building reusable components and maintainable codes. also, spend free time reading books about system architecture and clean coding.

## **Recent Experience**

#### Front-end Lead

Zoomit - Full-time Apr 2021 - Present Tehran, Iran

- Leading a team of 5 engineers working on the new zoomit mono-repo containing the new editorial, design systems, website, documentations and storybooks.
- Using Nx, TypeScript, Nextjs, Jest, Cypress, Storybook, Lexical, Zustand, react-hook-form and many other OSS to helps us at scale
- Around 60% of design systems are tested with Jest and TestingLibrary. we wrote tens of e2e tests for applications.
- We use Nx to manage our mono-repo containing more than 1.7 million lines of code and still conunting.

#### Front-end developer

KIAN IRANIAN STDG - Full-time

Sep 2020 – Apr 2021 Tehran, Iran

- Rewriting the web client of iGap messenger with Reactjs, Typescript, Redux, WebSocket and Material-Ui. I wrote around 40% of codebase. Structure Redux and other Logics. Converting class component to functional, groups, channels, forward message, iLand, authentication pages, setting tab, sticker, animated stickers, some of message boxes, many resuble components and utils are a part of my job. Currently planning for Beta release (https://web.igap.net
- Maintaining Parsian bank club().
- Coding part of iGap Doc (https://doc.igap.net/docs/Introduction) with Docusaurus v2, mdx, React.
- helping to build some internal tools and Back-End panels.

### **Education**

#### **Babol Noshirvani University of Technology**

Bachelor's degree - Computer Software Engineering 2023 - 2019

Babol, Iran

Learning a lot about computer sceince by reading refrence book and doing assignments. Compiler design, Operating system and Algorithm design were some of my favorite courses in university.

https://github.com/always-maap/Limoo-Lang https://github.com/always-maap/Python-Leet-Code https://github.com/always-maap/Threejs-Extended-Hanoi

### Technical Skills (in order)

#### Software Engineering

Typescript, Ecmascript, Python, Git, Docker, Eslint, Babel, Yarn, Lerna

#### Client (proficient)

React, Redux, styled-components, Sass, CSS, HTML, react-query, react-hook-form, react-native, PWA workbox

#### Industry

Data Structes, Algorithm, OOP, Command & Shell, MVC, DRY, MonoRepos, TDD, Design Patterns

#### Server (familiar)

Nodejs, GraphQL, Apollo Server, MongoDB, MySQL, Mongoose, TypeORM

### **Soft Skills**



# **Book and Cources**

Books are huge part of my life. here is list of my recent favorite books and videos.

(https://mammoth-lunch-a81.notion.site/34544fb5afb441249588426 55de9a436?v=bc8a51df2aa44702a24d7fb0e1601521)

- The Rust Programming Language Carol Nichols, Steve Klabnik
- Algorithms and Data Structures Masterclass Colt Steele
- SOLID: The Software Design and Architecture Khalil Stemmler
- Epic React Kent C. Dodds
- Intermediate TypeScript Mike North

# **Open Source**

I enjoy working in public and helping OSS. list of recent contributions

- TS-Collection: https://github.com/always-maap/TS-Collection
- Dayis-Jalali-Plugin: https://github.com/zoomit-org/Dayis-Jalali-Plugin
- Lexical: https://github.com/ianstormtaylor/slate
- Slate: https://github.com/ianstormtaylor/slate
- Tauri-Zeplin: https://github.com/always-maap/Tauri-Zeplin

### **Interests**

